# ARUN VISHNUNAMBOOTHIRI

Senior Software Engineer

<u>(408) 637 6414</u>

arun.vishnu.n@gmail.com



California



Software Engineer with more than 11 years of experience in diversified fields of Web Application Development/Maintenance. During this career, I have involved in various phases of Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) including Analysis, Design, Development and Testing

I am a JavaScript enthusiast and love building intuitive and performant web applications for the end users with a variety of web tech stacks - JavaScript, Node.js, HTML/CSS.

Outside of that, I love traveling, photography and having an interesting conversation over a great cup of coffee.

# WORK EXPERIENCES

#### **Senior Software Engineer**

Ellie Mae | Feb 2018 - Present

Ellie Mae is the leading cloud-based platform provider for the mortgage finance industry. As a Sr. Engineer, I work for the Next Gen Cloud applications team to build applications that help lenders across the industry originate more loans at lower costs, reduce time to close, and make smarter decisions.

- Successfully deliver EllieMae's web and mobile Loan origination applications built on AngularJS, React Redux tech stack (requirements, design, code, documentation, etc.)
- Technical ownership on multiple applications.
- Successfully Lead scurm teams to deliver 3 releases in 2019
- Provide sprint end product demos.
- Develop application using new tech stack Presented a session about the same to other teams which are getting on boarded to same tech stack.
- Roughly 75-80% hands-on coding and rest of the time helping the team for the ease of delivery.
- Contribute to early quality activities, including peer reviews of estimates, designs and code
- Identify, Resolve defects/bugs during testing, pre-production, production, and post-release patches
- · Work cross-functionally with various teams product management, various product lines, or business units to drive forward results

### **Senior Software Engineer**

GoPro | Dec 2017 - Feb 2018

• Building new and updating existing features for Web Login, Media Library, Account Center applications of GoPro using React, Node, ES2016+.

### Senior Associate, Web Applications

Cognizant - Wells Fargo | May 2016 - Dec 2017

Savings Application. Digital experiences that help customers build savings. The app enables the customers to map their savings needs, establish a safe to save amount, and engage the customer in an ongoing savings conversation.

- Developed single page frontend application
- Developed reusable components, plug-ins and responsive interfaces in custom JavaScript framework and React.

# SKILLS

#### **Technical**

JavaScript/ECMAScript 6 (ES6)/ES7/jQuery

React/Redux/Redux Saga/AngularJS

Node.js/Express

Object-oriented design

Single Page Applications (SPA)

Webpack, gulp, RequireJs, less, JsDoc

Karma, Jasmine, Jest

GIT, Perforce, Subversion (SVN)

MySQL

PHP/Zend Framework

Lead and deliver complex software systems

#### **Professional**

Confident Leader

**Effective Communication** 

Team Player

Strong Problem Solver

Good Time Management

### **EDUCATION**

#### **Bachelor of Technology**

SCT College of Engineering, University Kerala,

2003 - 2007

- Troubleshot errors and resolved issues in pre-production environments.
- Analyzed business requirements, provided feedback and developed plans to meet the requirements.
- Tracked long-term development and performed code reviews and merging

## **Senior Software Engineer**

Accenture | Sep 2010 - May 2016

Multiple projects for Accenture with varying roles that ranges from a developer to tech lead positions for various clients - Apple, Walt Disney, Cisco etc.

- As Technical Lead for one of the customer-facing applications helping Walt Disney internet customers plan thier vacations on Various Parks and Resorts.
- UI/UX development to create a seamless experience for a high traffic customer facing applications and performed maintenance fixes for the same.
- Sprint planning, pre-planning activities; Sprint Demos Presented major enhancements/changes to business and other teams.
- Performed code reviews for peers and junior developers. Documented project and development work.
- Implemented software change requests (CRs) to deploy new features and defect fixes into production environment.
- Onshore Coordinator and Technical lead for a Custom analytics application. AT&T Business team uses this to get valuable insights about visitors to applications and generate graphical/excel reports.
- UI Lead for web application used by Apple's Business to develop relationships with companies and contacts
- Created cross browser compatible web pages turning mockups into pixel-perfect HTML with photo editing tools and created well-organized CSS.

#### **Software Engineer**

QBurst Technologies | Oct2009 - Aug 2010

Qburst is a full-service software solutions provider that works with clients to maximize the effectiveness of their business through the adoption of digital technology. As a software engineer, I worked on developing and maintaining products for multiple clients.

- Developed Students Portal for Manchester Metropolitan University Business school. The
  application enables University tutors to provide guidance to the students for placement.
  Students can create and manage their online profile and can apply for jobs online. It has
  modules for continuous assessment and review of student profile. The application also allows
  users to create online video resumes.
- Wrote SQL queries that fetches data from a MySQL database for report generation modules.
- Worked in Agile team to design, develop and maintain different Web based applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript / jQuery, JSON, PHP and Java.
- Involved in developing RESTful web service client and server.
- Carried out application performance improvement used sprites, lossless compressions and optimized the existing SQL queries.
- Was involved in unit testing and application documentation creation.
- Developed video recording modules.
- Was responsible for deploying the application to staging and live servers.
- Designed the database identifying entity relationships and normalizations

#### **Software Engineer**

iTraitz IT Solutions | Mar 2008 – Aug 2009

- Worked with client and other developers to gather requirements, developing report generation modules.
- Created cron task for archiving reports with PHP and MySQL.
- Supported, maintained and improved the existing modules.

# CERTIFICATIONS

Zend PHP 5.3 ACN-Agile Foundation Level Certification.